When Andy met Edie, life imitated art.
Factory Girl is a drama, history film directed by George Hickenlooper.
In the mid-1960s, wealthy debutant Edie Sedgwick meets artist Andy Warhol.
She joins Warhol's famous Factory and becomes his muse.
Although she seems to have it all, Edie cannot have the love she craves from Andy, and she has an affair with
a charismatic musician, who pushes her to seek independence from the artist and the milieu.
Edie Sedgwick, played by Sienna Miller.
Andy Warhol, played by Guy Pearce.
Musician, played by Hayden Christensen.
Richie Berlin, played by Mena Suvari.
Chuck Wein, played by Jimmy Fallon.
Brigid Polk, played by Tara Summers.
Factory Girl is a 2006 American biographical film
directed by George Hickenlooper.
It is based on the rapid rise and fall of 1960s underground film star and socialite Edie Sedgwick
(Sienna Miller), known for her association with the artist Andy Warhol (Guy Pearce).
Factory Girl was released by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (through MGM Distribution Co.) on December 29, 2006, to
largely negative reviews from critics, who nonetheless praised Miller's performance as Sedgwick.
The film grossed $3.6 million against a $7 million budget.
The film explores themes of infidelity, new york city, gallery, alcohol, studio.
The tone is emotional.